Guide to the Central Washington University Ephemera Collection 1891-present (bulk 1960s-2000s)
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Ephemera Collection
1891-present (bulk 1960s-2000s)
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
EPH-0001
Central Washington University
6 cubic feet 10 legal-sized document cases, 1 oversized flat box Pamphlets, programs, advertisements, flyers, souvenirs, schedules, newsletters in fair to good condition
This collection contains ephemera related to Central Washington University. As ephemera, these items were created for short-term use, 1891 to the present.
Historical Note
The doors of the Washington State Normal School in Ellensburg opened in 1891. Mr. Benjamin Franklin Barge was the first principal of the school, which was founded to educate future elementary and junior high teachers. Classes were held at the Washington Public School until the normal school's first building, Barge Hall, opened in 1893. The normal school became Central Washington College of Education in 1937, Central Washington State College in 1961, and Central Washington University in 1977.
This collection comprises pamphlets, souvenirs, flyers, and other emphemeral material produced by or about Central Washington University, 1891 to the present.
Organized alphabetically by object title or originating department
Open to the public for educational research
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Central Washington University
Ellensburg (Wash.)
Central Washington University--History
Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
- 50th Reunion, 1967 (Box-folder 1-1)
- A Symposium, 1965-2003 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Abuse, circa 1980 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Academic Advisement, circa 1970 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Admissions, 1964-1978 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Admissions: Acceptance Information, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Admissions: One Student at a Time, circa 2000 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Admissions: Viewbook, 1981-1997 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Admissions: Your Future is Central, circa 2000 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Annual Contemporary Indian Art Exhibit, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Annual Symposium on American Values, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Associated Women Studies, 1944 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Association for Childhood Education (ACE), 1945-1946 (Box-folder 1-13)
- Athletics: Activities Planning Guide, 1960 (Box-folder 1-14)
- Athletics: Athletic Camp, 1997-2007 (Box-folder 1-15)
- Athletics: Banquet of Champions, 1997 (Box-folder 1-16)
- Athletics: Battle in Seattle, 2003-2006 (Box-folder 1-17)
- Athletics: Cat Tracks, 2009 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Athletics: Corporate Sponsors Kick-off BBQ, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Athletics: Nicholsons, 1960-1998 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Athletics: Special Reception, 1998 (Box-folder 2-4)
- Athletics: Sports Schedule, 1949-2017 (Box-folder 2-5)
- aviso, 2011 (Box-folder 2-6)
- Black Hall, 1998 (Box-folder 2-7)
- Black History Month, 2011-2013 (Box-folder 2-8)
- Bonds, 1968 (Box-folder 2-9)
- Bookstore, 1962-2012 (Box-folder 2-10)
- Budget Requests, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 2-11)
- Building Maintenance and Operating Procedures, 1969 (Box-folder 2-12)
- Business Administration, 1999 (Box-folder 2-13)
- Bulletin of Information, 1962 (Box-folder 2-14)
- Campus Life, 1995-2005 (Box-folder 2-15)
- Career Development Services, circa 2003-2022 (Box-folder 2-16)
- Careers in Science, 1955 (Box-folder 2-17)
- Caring, 1974 (Box-folder 2-18)
- Cars and Bikes on Campus, 1971-2012 (Box-folder 2-19)
- Célébrez le Paralléle 46 – Vins de Washington et de France, 2012 (Box-folder 2-20)
- Center for Student Empowerment, 2003-2012 (Box-folder 2-21)
- Center for the Preparation of School Personnel, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 2-22)
- Center for Teaching and Learning, circa 1998 (Box-folder 2-23)
- Central Connections, 2009 (Box-folder 2-24)
- The Central Express, 1985 (Box-folder 2-25)
- the central idea, 1964 (Box-folder 2-26)
- Central Investment Fund, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 2-27)
- Central Washington College of Education: Bulletins of Information, 1941-1960 (Box-folder 2-28)
- Central Washington College of Education: It’s Fun at CWCE, 1947 (Box-folder 2-29)
- Central Washington College of Education: Questions and Answers, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 2-30)
- Central Washington College of Education: War/Military, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 2-31)
- Central Washington University, 1976-2007 (Box-folder 2-32)
- Chimpanzee and Human Communication Institute, 1983-circa 1990 (Box-folder 3-1)
- Class Schedule, 1971 (Box-folder 3-2)
- Clubs, 1997-2007 (Box-folder 3-3)
- College Elementary School, 1939-1962 (Box-folder 3-4)
- College of Arts and Humanities, 1995-2011 (Box-folder 3-5)
- The College of Arts and Sciences, 1947-1963 (Box-folder 3-6)
- College of Education, 1944-1964 (Box-folder 3-7)
- College of Education, 2009 (Box-folder 3-8)
- Colloquium on Science and Society, 1969 (Box-folder 3-9)
- Committee Booklet, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3-10)
- Computer Service, 1964-1989 (Box-folder 3-11)
- Conference, 1970-1992 (Box-folder 3-12)
- Conference and Workshop, circa 1970-1978 (Box-folder 3-13)
- Cornerstone Program, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 3-14)
- Correspondence Bulletin, 1968 (Box-folder 3-15)
- Cultural Heritage Archive and Museum Project (CHAMP), circa 2000 (Box-folder 3-16)
- CWCE Visual Education, 1946 (Box-folder 3-17)
- CWCE Autographs, 1949 (Box-folder 3-18)
- CWU Evaluation and Assessment, 1998-2008 (Box-folder 3-19)
- CWU Law and Justice Alumni Newsletter, 2000 (Box-folder 3-20)
- Dedications, 1945-2009 (Box-folder 3-21)
- The Department of Business and Economics/Education, 1994-2012 (Box-folder 3-22)
- Department Pamphlets, circa 1980-2000 (Box-folder 3-23)
- Dining Services, 2003-2016 (Box-folder 4-1)
- Dining Services: Off-Campus Meal Plan, circa 1974 (Box-folder 4-2)
- Diversity Education Center, 1997-2009 (Box-folder 4-3)
- Donating, 1966-circa 2000 (Box-folder 4-4)
- Douglas Honors College, 1977 (Box-folder 4-5)
- Drug and Alcohol (Box-folder 4-6)
- Education Week, 1988 (Box-folder 4-7)
- Educational Opportunities Program, circa 1970 (Box-folder 4-8)
- Enrollment Management and Marketing Plan, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 4-9)
- Evening of Recognition / Leadership Luncheon, 2003 (Box-folder 4-10)
- Facilities Management Department, circa 1990 (Box-folder 4-11)
- Faculty, 1941-2020 (Box-folder 4-12)
- Faculty Employment Information, circa 1960 (Box-folder 4-13)
- Family Weekend, 2007 (Box-folder 4-14)
- F.D.R. Centennial Conference, 1982 (Box-folder 4-15)
- featuring the central idea, 1974 (Box-folder 4-16)
- First Year, 1992-2001 (Box-folder 4-17)
- First Year: New Student Convocation, 2013-2019 (Box-folder 4-18)
- First Year: New Student Week, 1964-2015 (Box-folder 4-19)
- Foreign Language Day, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 4-20)
- Graduate School, 1947-2012 (Box-folder 4-21)
- Golden Anniversary, 1941 (Box-folder 4-22)
- Handbooks: Advising, 2001-2005 (Box-folder 4-23)
- Handbooks: Special Project Proposals, circa 1970 (Box-folder 4-24)
- Handbooks: Staff, circa 1960s (Box-folder 5-1)
- Handbooks: Student Registration, 2004-2008 (Box-folder 5-2)
- Handbooks: Student Teachers, circa 1960s (Box-folder 5-3)
- Handbooks: Students, 1956-circa 1970s (Box-folder 5-4)
- Highlights, 1998 (Box-folder 5-5)
- Holiday Celebration, 2004-2012 (Box-folder 5-6)
- Homecoming 1962 Pamphlets and Invitations Twilight Zone Military Ball 1963 and Wildcat Decals, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5-7)
- Honor Society of Phi Kappa Phi, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 5-8)
- Housing: Campus Apartments, 1974-2003 (Box-folder 5-9)
- Housing: Family Housing, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 5-10)
- Housing: Married Student Housing, 1964-1974 (Box-folder 5-11)
- Housing: OWLS (On With Living Seniors!), 1978 (Box-folder 5-12)
- Human Trafficking in Washington State, 2012 (Box-folder 5-13)
- Illustrators at Work, 1947 (Box-folder 5-14)
- Imagine, circa 1990 (Box-folder 5-15)
- Inauguration, 1962-2000 (Box-folder 5-16)
- Insurance Plan, 1960-1993 (Box-folder 6-1)
- Instructional Observation and Demonstration (television), 1959 (Box-folder 6-2)
- Japanese Garden, circa 1993 (Box-folder 6-3)
- Jerrol’s, 2007 (Box-folder 6-4)
- Key Policy, 1992 (Box-folder 6-5)
- Khodadad (Khodi) Kaviani Persian Music Collection, 1999-2014 (Box-folder 6-6)
- Larson Gallery, 2010 (Box-folder 6-7)
- Le Cercle Parisien, 1966 (Box-folder 6-8)
- Library, 1973-circa 2000 (Box-folder 6-9)
- Library: Bouillon Library, circa 1960 (Box-folder 6-10)
- Library: CWSC Library, 1961 (Box-folder 6-11)
- Library: Friends at the Library, 2005-2011 (Box-folder 6-12)
- Library: How to, 1987 (Box-folder 6-13)
- Library: James E. Brooks Library Naming Ceremony, 2003 (Box-folder 6-14)
- Library: Sampler, 1973 (Box-folder 6-15)
- Library: Services for Faculty, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 6-16)
- Library: Tsungani Totem Pole, 1999 (Box-folder 6-17)
- Library and Media Center, circa 1970 (Box-folder 6-18)
- Map, 1960-circa 1990 (Box-folder 6-19)
- McNair Scholars, circa 2000-2003 (Box-folder 6-20)
- Memorandum form the President’s Office, 1948 (Box-folder 6-21)
- Museum of Culture and Environment, 2012 (Box-folder 6-22)
- Music Department, 1942-2012 (Box-folder 6-23)
- My CWU, 2014 (Box-folder 6-24)
- New Science Building, 1998 (Box-folder 6-25)
- Nursing School Short Course, 1942 (Box-folder 6-26)
- Our Booming College Enrollment, 1956 (Box-folder 6-27)
- Overview, circa 1990 (Box-folder 6-28)
- Planned Parenthood (Box-folder 7-1)
- Post Cards, circa 2000 (Box-folder 7-2)
- Presidential Search, 1991 (Box-folder 7-3)
- President’s Reception, 2009 (Box-folder 7-4)
- President’s Report, 1996-2006 (Box-folder 7-5)
- The Quest, 2004 (Box-folder 7-6)
- Reach for the Stars, 1997 (Box-folder 7-7)
- Recycle (Box-folder 7-8)
- Re-Entry Student’s Resource Guide, 1991 (Box-folder 7-9)
- Reservation Card, 1996 (Box-folder 7-10)
- Reserve Officer Training Core (ROTC), 2002-2013 (Box-folder 7-11)
- Residence Halls, 1940-2013 (Box-folder 7-12)
- Residence Halls: Barge Hall, 1993 (Box-folder 7-13)
- Residence Halls: Cluster College, 1969 (Box-folder 7-14)
- Residence Halls: Courson Hall, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 7-15)
- Residence Halls: Kamola Hall, 2003 (Box-folder 7-16)
- Retirement Association, 1991-2002 (Box-folder 7-17)
- Reunion, 1985 (Box-folder 7-18)
- RE: View, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 7-19)
- Safety Awareness, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 7-20)
- Sarah Spurgeon Gallery, 2006-2011 (Box-folder 7-21)
- Scholarships, 1962-2003 (Box-folder 7-22)
- Senior Ventures, 2000 (Box-folder 7-23)
- Service Award Program, 2003 (Box-folder 7-24)
- Shakespeare on Film, 2000 (Box-folder 7-25)
- Speakers, 1964-2006 (Box-folder 7-27)
- Speakers: College of Arts and Humanities Speakers Series, 2007-2011 (Box-folder 7-28)
- Speakers: Distinguished Visiting Professor, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 7-29)
- Speakers: Lion Rock Visiting Writers, 2009-2012 (Box-folder 7-30)
- Special Education Technology Center, circa 2000 (Box-folder 8-1)
- State Funding, 1968-circa 1980 (Box-folder 8-2)
- Stop Sexual Harassment, 1989-2006 (Box-folder 8-3)
- Strategic Plan, 1996-2011 (Box-folder 8-4)
- Student Employment, 1978-circa 1990 (Box-folder 8-5)
- Student Health and Counseling Center, 1998 (Box-folder 8-6)
- Student Union Recreation Center (SURC), 2006-2008 (Box-folder 8-7)
- Study Abroad/AAUP, 1967-2012 (Box-folder 8-8)
- Study Abroad: CWU Direct Exchange, 2000 (Box-folder 8-9)
- Study Abroad: Tour Europe, 1957 (Box-folder 8-10)
- Study of Migrant and Indian Education, 1971 (Box-folder 8-11)
- Summary of Budget Request, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 8-12)
- Summer: Laughing Horse Summer Theatre, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 8-13)
- Summer: Housing, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 8-14)
- Summer: Music Camp, 1954 (Box-folder 8-15)
- Summer Camp: Easter Seal Camp for Crippled Children, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 8-16)
- Summer Session, 1946-2020 (Box-folder 8-17)
- Summer Session: Conservation and Outdoor Education Workshop, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 8-18)
- Summer Session: Courses on How to Teach, circa 1960 (Box-folder 8-19)
- Summer Session: Energy, 1978 (Box-folder 8-20)
- Summer Session: Home Economics, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 8-21)
- Summer Session: Industrial Arts, 1963 (Box-folder 8-22)
- Summer Session: Music Education, 1945 (Box-folder 8-23)
- Summer Session: NDEA, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 8-24)
- Summer Session: Recreation Program, 1960 (Box-folder 8-25)
- Summer Session: Science and Outdoor Education Camp, 1952 (Box-folder 8-26)
- Summer Session: A Summer Workshop, 1949-1959 (Box-folder 9-1)
- Summer Workshop: Modern Junior High School Program, 1956 (Box-folder 9-2)
- Supplement to the Daily Record, 1994-2007 (Box-folder 9-3)
- Symposia, 1988-1996 (Box-folder 9-4)
- Teaching: A Career for You, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 9-5)
- Telephone Safety Planning, 1995 (Box-folder 9-6)
- Theatre Department, 1975-2012 (Box-folder 9-7)
- Transfer Guide, 2005-2010 (Box-folder 9-8)
- Transforming Lives, 2007 (Box-folder 9-9)
- Twenty Years of Service with Central Washington College of Education, 1951 (Box-folder 9-10)
- UFC Elections, circa 2000 (Box-folder 9-11)
- Washington State Normal School, 1899-1938 (Box-folder 9-12)
- Washington State Normal School: Athletics, 1922-1926 (Box-folder 9-13)
- Washington State Normal School: Campus Glimpses/ College Bulletin, 1928-1936 (Box-folder 9-14)
- Washington State Normal School: Courses Tabulated, 1915 (Box-folder 9-15)
- Washington State Normal School: Government, 1911-1918 (Box-folder 9-16)
- Washington State Normal School: Pennant, Leather Post Card, 1930 (Box-folder 9-17)
- Washington State Normal School: Programs, Memos, and Faces, 1895-1938 (Box-folder 9-18)
- Washington State Normal School: Schedule and Attendance, 1895-circa 1910 (Box-folder 9-19)
- Washington State Normal School: Student’s Handbook, 1898-1899 (Box-folder 9-20)
- Washington State Normal School: Summer Session, 1914-1935 (Box-folder 9-21)
- Washington State Normal School: Women’s League, 1927-1932 (Box-folder 9-22)
- Welcome Wildcat Walk, 2012 (Box-folder 9-23)
- Wellness Center, 1995-circa 2000 (Box-folder 9-24)
- Wildcat Habitat, 2003-2006 (Box-folder 9-25)
- Women in Politics, 1993-2010 (Box-folder 9-26)
- World Languages Day, 2009 (Box-folder 9-27)
- Yakima Basin Center, 1990 (Box-folder 9-28)
- Oversized, 1990 (Box 10)
- Accreditation of University, 2017 (Box 11-1)
- Public Safety and Police Services Department, 2001 (Box 11-2)
- Symposium on Undergraduate Research and Creative Expression SOU, 2019 (Box 11-3)